Kavita Ganeshan

PERSONAL DATA

ADDRESS: B-701, Pranay Sudarshan Apts, Joshi lane Ghatkopar East, Mumbai - 400077, India

PHONE: +91-9920552210

NATIONALITY Indian

DATE OF BIRTH 08.04.1987

EMAIL: kavlata@gmail.com

GITHUB: https://github.com/kavlata

LINKEDIN: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/kavita-ganeshan/22/616/711

EDUCATION

JUNE 2010 MTech in Information Technology, IIIT, Bengaluru CGPA: 3.33/4.00

JUNE 2008 Btech in COMPUTER SCIENCE, PVPPCOE, Mumbai GPA: 72%

2003-2004 HSC Maharashtra Board, Mumbai GPA: **82.50**% SSC Maharashtra Board, Mumbai GPA: **89.20**%

SUMMARY

I am Senior Data Scientist at Cuddle.ai-Fractal Analytics Pvt Ltd. I have 7 years of industrial experience in Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning.

My current role is in the cross-roads of recommendation, ranking algorithms, software engineering, machine learning, data science and natural language processing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current SEP 2015 Senior Data Scientist-NLP at Fractal Analytics PVT LTD - CUDDLE.AI Mumbai, India

News Recommendation

I have designed and developed an engine to recommend News to users based on their business interests. I have setup a pipeline using word2vec based relevance module, minhash-LSH based deduplication module, collborative filtering based recommendation and ranking based on the feedback stats from Redshift AWS.

The News digest is being used by 50 users within the company and 200 client users who have been actively participating for over 7 months. My ensemble algorithm has increased the accuracy of Relevance by 60 percent from our baseline. My recommendation engine has led to a 3 percent increase in user engagement calculated based on user's interactions.

I am also involved in building automated contextual ontology for the business and to enrich it with insights extracted from News $\,$

APR 2015 - SEP 2015

Senior Software Engineer at Germinait Solutions PVT LTD, Mumbai, India $Algorithms\ Team$

I was part of Algorithms team and my role was to extract user intent from tweets.

I had implemented one-vs-all multiclass SVM classifier. Daily the engine would process 10 batches of data, each of size 20 MB. The sparsity of the data was - 1 user intent per 600 tweets (approx). My algorithm performed with an accuracy of 0.8

AUG 2011 - MAR 2015

Senior Software Engineer at Creditpointe Services PVT Ltd, Pune, India Semantic Team

I was part of Semantics Team. I had worked on query interpretation, semi-supervised context based sentiment analysis (using NLP techniques), topic modelling using the grammar in the corpora, semi-supervised ontology generation, automatic discovery of ontology using Wikipedia, relation extraction, sentiment analysis, logical deduplication and co-reference resolution. I deployed above solutions for Financial, Pharma and Legal contracts domain.

AUG 2010 - AUG 2011

Information Retrieval Engineer at WEB 18 PVT LTD Mumbai, India

I was part of Information retrieval team and worked on query segmentation, extracting quotations mentioned in news articles, Named entity extraction, classifying News articles and clustering similar content.

DEC 2009 - JUN 2010

Internship at GISE lab, IITB

I worked under Prof.N.L.Sarda in the GISE lab in IIT Bombay, India. My work helped me publish couple of papers in reputed journals.

I had presented my internship work in TCS innovation labs under the supervision of Dr.Arun Pande. (Head of TCS innovation labs, Mumbai, India)

DATA CHALLENGE

CODS 2017

Differentiating Code-Borrowing from Code-Mixing.

I was a runner up in this data challenge. I submitted this as a team entry. I presented this work in CODS/COMAD 2017 conference in IITM. Details are here https://cuddledatascience.github.io/CODS2017/

SCHOLARSHIPS AND PUBLICATIONS

Nov 2010 Keyword Search in geo-spatial databases

Submitted in demo paper category in ACM SIG SPATIAL 2010, USA

SEP 2010 Developing IITB Smart CampusGIS Grid

Submitted in paper category in A2CWIC 2010, India

2005-2006 Awarded the Sir Ratan Tata Scholarship for academic excellence in 2nd Year

bachelors program

2012-2013 Received Best Employee award in Creditpointe Services.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python

NLP/ML Libraries: Stanford Parser, NER, Coreference resolution, Wordnet, sentiwordnet, conceptnet, semgrex, Opennlp, Wikipedia

Frameworks/Libraries/Tools: Lucene, Solr, LibSVM, Word2Vec

Databases : MySQL, PostgreSQL

Editors: vi

Cloud: AWS

AWS - $SQS,\,EC2,\,ECS.$ Microsoft cognitive API - text

Continuous Integration: Jenkins, GIT, Docker

Others: Latex, Intellij

Operating Systems: Mac, Linux

Experimented with: R,Python - Scikitlearn, nltk, Gensim, Numpy, Pandas

Neo4j, MongoDB

Distributed computing: Spark MLlib

Project Management tools: JIRA, Confluence, Mattermost, Agile

Deep learning toold: Keras